And it was written in the Covenant of Primus,
根据原始天尊圣约记载
that "when the 47 spheres align,
“当四十七颗星球连成一线之际
a perpetual conflict will culminate upon a world forged from chaos,
无尽的纷争 终将席卷某个混沌的世间
and the weak shall perish in the shadow of a rising darkness."
弱者随之消亡 黑暗势力崛起并笼罩四方”
No, sky is raining fire?
天上还会下火球吗？
Goes without say,
不用多说
it is a doom prophecy after all.
这的确是个可怕的末世论
I say it's a load of hooey.
要我说 这纯粹是无稽之谈
I'd always assume the ancients were referring to our home planet,
我一直以为 古人所说的是我们的母星
but being that Cybertron has been dark for eons...
但既然塞博特恩早在千万年前就陷入黑暗…
And considering what has befallen this planet since Megatron's arrival here...
而且 威震天到来之后 这个星球变得多灾多难…
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
哇…
We've known about these superstitions for ages and never gave them a second thought.
这些神论我们能倒背如流 可从没当回事儿
Why all the ominous rumblings now?
现在干嘛这么疑神疑鬼的？
Because the planetary alignment to which the prophecy refers is nearly upon us.
因为预言中提到的星球串联现象 近在眼前
And it would seem its end point... is Earth.
而且看起来它的末端…是地球
Eh... Crazy coincidence, yeah, right?
呃…巧合得太离谱了 是吧？
How long are we talking?
还有多久？
A few days, at most.
最多不过几天时间
However unsettling this revelation may be,
这个事实固然令人不安
I am more concerned about those who might believe that the prophecy speaks to them alone.
但我更担心另一些人 他们很可能利用预言图谋不轨
I did not seek out the blood of Unicron to simply keep my spark aflame,
我一心寻找宇宙大帝之血 不是为了苟且偷生
but to rule undead armies, and conquer worlds!
而是要统领不死大军 征服所有世界！
And to accomplish that,
要想达成夙愿
I require more than this mere sliver which lies within me.
只靠我体内这一小块碎片 是远远不够的
So... where is my Dark Energon?!
那么…我的黑暗能量在哪儿？！
Out there, Lord Megatron.
就在星云之间 威震天陛下
Just waiting for you to reach out and pluck it!
早晚都是您的囊中之物！
But you shouldn't push yourself so hard.
但您不必如此勉强自己
You've had setbacks.
您大病初愈
You were in stasis.
刚从平衡状态苏醒
Precisely why I must make up for lost time!
正因为这样 我才必须抓紧时间！
I can see the future, vividly!
我眼中的未来…无比清晰！
But I must ensure its outcome.
可我必须确保它成为现实
For I am the rising darkness,
因为我就是那个崛起的黑暗势力
of which the prophecy speaks!
预言必将由我来印证！
Pass, um, kid in costume, balloon,
跳过 嗯… 小孩捣鬼 气球而已
nope, hold,
不对 等等
the camera sure loves Bee.
小蜂果然很上镜
What can you do?
有什么办法？
When you're a superstar,
一旦当上超级巨星
You're paparazzi bait.
就成了狗仔队的靶子
Wait. Is that Bumblebee?
等一下 那是大黄蜂吗？
On a conspiracy website.
这是个揭秘网站
Where users post evidents of close encounters,
用户可以发布接触外星人的证据
but we have it under control, Ratchet.
不过包在我们身上 救护车
We just scrub and replace Bee with... Mars Cat says, "Take me to your feeder!"
我们把小蜂的照片抹掉 换成… “我是火星猫 带我去吃饭吧！”
Ratchet actually laughed?
救护车居然笑了？
Um, Optimus, you wanna see something funny?
嗯 擎天柱 想看点有趣的吗？
No.
不想
Don't take it personally.
别往心里去
Primes are built that way.
领袖就是那个样子
Never seen Optimus laugh, cry or lose his cool.
从没见过擎天柱笑 哭 或者有失风度
While Optimus certainly keeps his emotions in check,
擎天柱从来不会轻易表露他的情感
I've known him far longer than any of you have.
但我比你们中任何一个都更熟悉他
And he was different before he was made a Prime.
成为领袖之前 他不是这样的
Optimus wasn't always a Prime?
擎天柱没有一直当领袖吗？
On Cybertron one isn't born into greatness,
在塞博特恩 伟人并不是天生的
rather, one must earn it.
而是靠努力争取来的
So, different, how?
那么 怎么个不同法？
We're talking party animal?
他以前是派对狂人吗？
No, no, Optimus was more like... Jack.
不 不 从前的擎天柱更像是…杰克
What? I'm nothing like Op...
什么？我一点也不像擎…
Prime, Those tech-guys my department's been tracking.
擎天柱 还记得我们追踪的那些家伙吗
We figured it was MECH on account of the stealth tactics.
我们原以为是机械党 因为作案手段非常相似
Until moments ago when a security feed at the Pennington-Ebbs Particle Collider captured this.
可是不久前
Soundwave.
声波
Raf can swap that out for you with a funny cat.
拉夫可以帮你把声波换成小猫咪
The Con without a face made off with the cutting-edge phase conductor.
这个“没脸”的虎子 偷走了最先进的相位导体
Here is a punch list of everything else we've confirmed stolen to date.
这里有一份清单 列出了目前为止确认被盗的所有物品
Plasma injector, Neutron Shield, Tesseract.
等离子喷射器 中子盾 超正方体
There is only one thing missing if they are intending to build...
还差一样东西 他们就能建造…
The Decepticon space bridge 2.0 is nearly ready to launch.
霸天虎太空桥2.0版 即将竣工启动
All we require is...
我们只差一个…
what Soundwave said--
如声波所说…
an ample power source.
充足的动力源
This one lies within a highly fortefied location...
这东西所在的基地有重兵把守…
by human standards.
不过是区区人类而已
I could tunnel in.
我可以打通一条隧道
The time of prophecy is nearly upon us.
预言成真的时刻就快到了！
We could no longer afford stealth.
没时间去偷鸡摸狗了
Prime, the Cons really stepped out at this time.
擎天柱 虎子们这次真的坐不住了
They hit a U.S. military lab,
他们袭击了一个美军实验室
Our boys in green will fend them off till your team shows.
弟兄们会尽力顶住 等待你们到场
Agent Fowler, I fear that Megatron's desperation may be at its zenith.
福勒探员 我担心 威震天已经到了破釜沉舟的地步
And you know that I cannot condone even a single human casualty.
你很清楚 我绝不容许任何一名人类惨遭不测
Fowler here.
我是福勒
Evacuate all personnel, immediately.
疏散所有人员 立即执行
Retreat.
撤退！
Lord Megatron, package secured,
威震天陛下 货已到手
but the Autobots have arrived.
但是汽车人来了
Ah! Prepare the warship for rendezvous.
啊！将战舰开往会合地点
The package will be ready for pick-up.
务必当场收货
Bumblebee, the team may require back-up.
大黄蜂 他们可能需要支援
They are three kliks north from your current position just on the high way.
距离你当前位置三分钟路程 就在高速路上
If you drop Raf at the exit ramp,
你可以在出口让拉夫下车
I can bridge him back to base from there.
我从那儿把他传送回基地
It's OK, Bee.
没关系 小蜂
We'll go racing another time.
我们可以改天再赛车
Well, well.
哎呀呀
A foolish scout is stray from the ranks.
一个愚蠢的侦察兵掉队了
Optimus.
擎天柱
Megatron.
威震天
Do you not see the folly in trying to force a prophecy to fruition?
你知不知道 强行把预言变为现实 是种愚蠢的行为？
Why leave matters to fate,
干嘛要听天由命呢
if one can forge one's own destiny?
我的命运我做主 难道不好吗？
Ah, speaking of fate...
啊 说到命运…
Raf!
拉夫！
He is breathing, barely.
他还在呼吸 但很微弱
Ah, ha, it would seem I swatted a bee and squashed a bug.
啊哈 看来我不仅拍了一只黄蜂 还捏死一只臭虫
Bee, no!
小蜂 别！
Ratchet, bridge us back now!
救护车 快把我们传送回去！
We must have an Autobot down.
一定是有汽车人受伤了
Arcee, attend to Rafael and Bumblebee.
阿尔茜 照顾好拉斐尔 还有大黄蜂
Raf?
拉夫？
No!
不！
What happened?
怎么回事？
Megatron.
是威震天
Quickly, into my laboratory.
快 送进我的实验室
Ah, Rafael isn¡¯t responding.
啊 拉斐尔没有反应
We must run diagnostics of his assemblage, eh...
必须全面检测他的零件 呃…
vital status.
生命机能
Ah, my tools.
啊 我的工具
They're all wrong!
全都派不上用场！
We need to call my mom.
应该叫我妈来
Your mother may be a nurse,
你妈妈虽然是个护士
but does she know anything about the effects of energon on the human body?
但她知道能量会对人类身体 造成什么影响吗？
What? Do you know anything about the human body?
那你又对人类身体了解多少？
Mom it¡®s urgent.
妈妈 有急事
The weak will perish.
弱者会消亡
Be strong, Rafael.
坚强点 拉斐尔
The power source will be ready in no time, Lord Megatron.
动力源即刻准备就绪 威震天陛下
We¡¯re nearly at the construction site.
我们很快就能到达建造工地了
Nearly isn' t good enough.
还是不够快
The spheres are aligning.
星球即将完成串联
I must not miss my moment to...
我不能错过时机 去…
Lord Megatron? Are you alright?
威震天陛下？您还好吧？
Yet again.
又来了
It is as if I can hear Unicron¡¯s thoughts.
我好像能听到宇宙大帝的思想
Unicron? The Chaos Bringer?
宇宙大帝？那个混沌之神？
They say dark energon is his blood.
听说 黑暗能量就是他的血液
Ha, whatever.
哈 管他呢
Complete the space bridge.
快完成太空桥
There is something I must attend to.
我还有件要事去办
Does he seem to be "losing it"?
他是不是看起来…神神叨叨的？
A bit...
有那么一点…
Mom, thank...
妈妈 谢…
Grab my bag.
拿我的包来
Measuring the extent of the absorption should determine the proper course of treatment.
先检测出他吸收了多少能量 才能决定正确的治疗方案
If I don't get this boy stabilized now,
如果不赶快稳定这孩子的病情
he will not leave this table alive.
他不可能活着走下手术台
Do you understand me?
你明白吗？
Ah...
呃…
Bee, listen.
小蜂 听着
You think I don¡¯t know how it feels to watch a partner...
你以为我愿意眼睁睁看着搭档…
harmed?
受伤吗？
Revenge won't help Raf right now.
眼下 复仇是帮不了拉夫的
You need to keep your emotions in check.
你得控制你的情绪
Ratchet, how is Rafael?
救护车 拉斐尔怎么样了？
It is too soon to know.
现在还不能断言
He's in good hands.
你的医术高明
Not mine. Optimus,
不是我 擎天柱
curse my cybertronian pride.
塞博特恩式的傲气让我目中无人
We've accepted these human into our lives,
我们已经接纳人类走进我们的生活
yet I've bothered to learn so little about their science or medicine.
但我却对他们的科学和医术…不屑一顾
Pull yourself together, old friend,
振作起来 老朋友
Rafael needs you.
拉斐尔需要你
And I have grown to need him.
我也变得越来越离不开他了
Lock on to my coordinates and activate the ground bridge.
锁定我的坐标 启动环陆桥
Ready.
准备好了
Bulkhead, return to base.
隔板 返回基地
There is something I must do.
我还有事情要做
Eh, serious?
呃 真的吗？
I have been foolish not to see what history has proven over and over again...
长久以来我过于一厢情愿 没有意识到 历史总在不断地重演…
that Autobots and Decepticons will never mend their ways.
汽车人和霸天虎永远不可能志同道合
If there can be no diplomatic solution to this perpetual conflict,
如果没法通过协商解决这场 旷日持久的冲突
then I must not allow more darkness to fall upon this,
那么我不能再容忍黑暗势力摧毁这里
or any planet.
以及任何一个星球
Megatron must be destroyed!
必须消灭威震天！
I have come for Megatron and him alone.
我只是来讨伐威震天一个人的
Stand down and be spared.
想活命的 就给我让开！
The flaming mountain in my visions.
我见过这座喷火的高山！
As if it summoned me here... Guided me!
应该是它在召唤着我…指引着我！
This is where I am to position my space bridge.
我的太空桥就该建在这里
The place from whence,
从这个地方
I am to harvest dark energon.
我可以尽情地收集黑暗能量！
Megatron, I am here, on your ship.
威震天 是我 我在你的船上
Come and face me!
来和我做个了断吧！
The place in which I am to defeat...
在这个地方 我即将击败…
the last of the Primes.
最后一位领袖！
Hear this,
听着
any Decepticon who lays a hand on Optimus Prime
有哪个霸天虎胆敢动擎天柱一根汗毛
will answer to me.
我都要亲自处决他！
Soundwave, lock onto my coordinates,
声波 锁定我的坐标
and lead my opponent to his destiny.
送我的老对手来接受他的命运吧！
Jack, help me get Raf to the car,
杰克 帮我抬拉夫上车
he's going to the emergency room.
必须送他去急救室
Nurse Darby,
达比护士
your doctors won't be able to comprehend what's afflicting him--
人类医生不会明白 折磨他的是什么东西
not without a decade of study.
他们至少要研究十几年
I don't have time to argue.
我没时间吵架
The effects of an energon blast on an Autobot can be devastating enough.
能量炮的威力足以让一名汽车人当场身亡
But this is a human.
更何况他是人类
I'm not getting any readings.
没有能量读数
How could I not have seen this?
我怎么没想到呢？
Rafael's been infected with dark energon.
感染拉斐尔的应该是黑暗能量才对
Megatron, today you answer for your crimes against Cybertron and against humanity.
威震天 今天你必须服法 向塞博特恩和人类低头认罪
One shall stand.
只有一个能活命
And one shall fall.
另一个必须死
You, Optimus Prime!
就是你 擎天柱！
If dark energon is devouring Raf from the inside out,
既然黑暗能量正在侵蚀拉夫体内的器官
we must expel it, and fast,
我们必须清除它 要尽快
the only possible way I know.
我知道唯一的可行办法
I need energon.
我需要能量！
Wait. You said energon was devastating to humans.
等一下 你说过 能量对人体是致命的
Under normal circumstances, quite.
在一般情况下的确会造成伤害
But I'm relying upon the dark matter currently invading Rafael's body to meet it head on.
不过我要利用入侵拉斐尔身体的黑暗能量 来中和损伤
Your defeat here was foreseen by the ancients.
先人早已经预见到 你会在此败北
What was it they wrote?
他们说什么来着？
"The weak shall perish"?
“弱者随之消亡”？
Do not believe everything you read.
尽信书 不如无书
I need him over here, now!
把他推过来 快！
Pulse rate is stabilizing.
脉搏稳定下来了
Bee.
小蜂
Optimus, we did it.
擎天柱 我们成功了
My destiny...
我的命运…
This isn't how it's supposed to end.
不该就这么草草收场！
On the contrary, Megatron...
恰恰相反 威震天…
I could not have allowed this to end otherwise.
我不允许有其他的结局
Bulkhead, you let Optimus face Megatron alone?
隔板 你让擎天柱一个人去对付威震天？
I didn't have a choice.
我没别的选择
It could be a trap.
这可能是陷阱
We need to get a fix on his location.
我们得找到他的位置
How was it that you put it, Optimus?
你刚才的大话是怎么说的 擎天柱？
"I could not have allowed this to end otherwise?"
“我不允许有其他的结局”？
I'm locked on to Optimus' signal.
我已经锁定了擎天柱的信号
Wait, how is this possible?
等一下 这怎么可能？
What? What is it?
什么？怎么了？
We need to get Optimus out of there, now!
必须让擎天柱离开那里 快！
Haha... Well, well.
哈哈哈…哎呀呀
It seems the blood of Unicron I've been seeking is not out there,
看来我苦苦寻找的宇宙大帝之血 不是在星云之间
but rather, right here!
而是就在…我的脚下！
Dark energon... erupting from the Earth?
黑暗能量…居然从地球内部喷发出来？